[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community
In this module, Emily showed us how to build product recommenders and
在这个模块中，艾米丽为我们展示了如何搭建一个产品推荐系统以及
algorithms associated with recommender systems.
跟推荐系统相关的算法
Now, we're gonna build a notebook to recommend songs
现在 让我们来建立一个Notebook 用来推荐
we might want to listen to.
我们可能想要听的歌曲
This is gonna be really quite cool.
这将会非常酷
Okay, so this is going to be the, we're gonna rename our notebook here.
好的 就是在这里了 我们可以在这里重命名我们的Notebook
This is the Song recommender.
这个叫歌曲推荐系统
So again, I'm going to hide the header and
像之前一样 我将会隐藏页眉和
hide the toolbar to show you this a little more space.
工具栏 这样我们会有更多的空间
And as usual, we're gonna start by importing graphlab.
照例我们从导入graphlab开始
Okay, let's start here.
好的 从这开始了
And the first thing that we're gonna do is load some music data.
首先我们要做的是加载音乐数据
So, we're gonna load music data.
加载音乐数据
This is a really cool dataset, it's called the Million Song Dataset.
这是个很棒的数据库  叫做百万歌库
And we're gonna create a variable called song_data.
然后我们创建一个叫song_data的变量
It's gonna store it.
它是用来存储的
And we're gonna have a graphlab.SFrame where
然后我们用graphlab.SFrame来
we're reading it and this is some data that dropped.
读入 这是载入的一些数据
So here we are, we're reading it and so
这里， 我们读取了这些数据然后
let's start doing a little bit of data exploration.
就可以开始一些数据检索了
So let's do some exploring over
让我们检索一下
a friend data here, music data.
其中一帧数据 一帧音乐数据
So first thing that we're gonna do, as usual,
那么首先我们要做的 像之前一样，
is take the song_data and take a look at the first few lines of this table.
是提取song_data来看看这个表格中的前几行
And so here's what the song data looks like.
这就是音乐数据的内容
A user for user ID.
一个用来标记用户身份的user变量
Listen to a song once or twice.
听一首歌的次数是一次还是两次
This is the title of the song, this is the artist and
这个是歌名 这个是歌手名称 还有
this is the song itself.
这个是歌曲本身
The title is the title of the record mentioned.
这个标题是专辑名称
And so, as we can see, we just have
因此 就像我们看到的这样 我们只有
a table that shows us how often each person listens to different songs.
一个显示着每个人听不同歌曲的频率的表格
And then we're gonna use this to build a recommender
我们要用这个来建立一个推荐系统
that finds out other songs you might be interested in listening to.
用来找出其他你可能有兴趣的歌曲
And we're gonna explore a couple different types of recommenders
我们会尝试一些不同类型的推荐系统
as Emily shared with us in the module.
就像艾米丽在这个模块中跟我们分享过的那些一样
So as usual I'm going to, I like showing the histogram on the notebook itself.
照例 我喜欢展示一下笔记本自身的直方图
So I'm gonna do graphlab.canvas.set_target and
所以我要调用graphlab.canvas.set_target和
I'm gonna say a ipynb.
在这命名ipynb
And then after we done that I'm gonna take my song_data.
这之后我再回到我的song_data变量
And I'm going to look at particular column, let's say the song column and
我将会针对一个特定的列 比如说歌曲列 然后
type.show in it, which is gonna show me
对它调用type.show函数 这会显示
a histogram of the different songs and how often they're played.
基于不同歌曲播放次数的直方图
And here we are.
结果在这里
So, this is the different songs by title, and
这里是不同歌曲的标题 而
you see how this song here was played 5,970 times.
你可以看到这里这首歌被播放了5970次
This Bjork song was played 5,281 times.
这首比约克的歌被播放了5281次
This song here, this is a Brazilian song.
这里这首是一首巴西歌曲
TVC by Catola, 3,185 times.
Catola的TVC 3185次
And so some people really like their songs and they play them a lot.
所以有些人非常喜欢听他们的歌并且反复听很多次
So this is the kind of data we're looking at, and
这就是我们想要的数据
if you take a quick look at this song data you'll see at the length.
如果你快速查看一下这个音乐数据 你可以看看它的长度
You see we're talking about here 1.1 million songs.
可以看到我们这里有110万首歌
So million song user pair, so this is ratings, song ratings.
也就是百万对歌曲和用户的条目 这里的条目对应的是歌曲的评分
And this is what the dataset is, a pretty large dataset.
这就是这个数据库 一个挺大的数据库
But we're gonna do some things together on this large data set right here.
我们来一起处理这个大型数据库吧
So let's ask, let's do a little bit more exploration.
让我们再稍稍探索一下
So we said for each user, there's 1 million,
我们说过对每个用户
about a million ratings or a million number of listens.
有大概1百万个评分或者1百万次播放
Let's see how many users are involved here.
让我们看看总共有多少用户
So, I'm going to, let's say,
我假设有
oops, ##Count number of users.
哎呀 计算用户数
So, in doing this, I'm gonna show you another little trick which is useful
用这个操作 我将会展示另一个有用的小技巧
as you're exploring your own dataset.
你以后自己处理数据的时候可以用
So, I am gonna create a new array here for users.
我在这创建一个新的用户向量
And this is going to take the song data that
这个向量会从我们现有的音乐数据中
we have and look at the user_id column.
查看用户名user_id那一列
And I'm gonna ask you apply the unique command.
然后对它调用unique命令
And what the unique command does is select out of all these users,
而unique命令的作用是选择所有这些用户
just shows the unique different users that we have.
只输出其中不重复的用户名
Just all the unique ones.
只有所有的独立用户
And so, if I ask for the length of users,
因此 如果我问起用户列表的长度
you should see that we have 66,346 unique users
你应该能看到我们总共有66346个独立用户
in this dataset with 1 million different song.
而在这个数据库中总共有1百万首不同的歌
You think about ratings, but number of times you listen to some,
你想的是评分项 而不是听同一首歌的次数
song activity rows.
以及歌曲相关活动的数据行
[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community